<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hasaber8</title>
    <link>https://hasaber.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Hasaber8</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Rohan Hasabe</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 10:24:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hasaber.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Motorola One Power aka Chef Custom Rom Flashing Guide</title>
      <link>https://hasaber.me/posts/chef-flashing-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 10:24:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hasaber.me/posts/chef-flashing-guide/</guid>
      <description>In this guide we will be installing LineageOS official build. (Same guide can be used to flash any other custom rom!) Prerequisite:-  Download LineageOS builds for chef from here:- (https://download.lineageos.org/chef) As Google apps are not included with the Rom download them from here:- (https://opengapps.org/), select ARM64 Android10 Nano Gapps. Official TWRP builds from:- (https://dl.twrp.me/chef/twrp-3.4.0-0-chef.img.html) Copy-Partition Zip; VERY IMPORTANT FOR FLASHING ROM COMING FROM STOCK. (https://drive.google.com/file/d/1_3NEgeTVujvFAfRs8Gdd0Ft0yRf9YjyJ/view?usp=sharing)    I expect you people already have necessary adb and fastboot drivers installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Violet PE June Update-2 Changelog!</title>
      <link>https://hasaber.me/posts/pe-violet-june-update-2-changelog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 13:51:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hasaber.me/posts/pe-violet-june-update-2-changelog/</guid>
      <description>Device Side changes:-  Camera Improvements. Audio Improvements. Removed MODEM throttle configs so your whatsapp call doesn&amp;rsquo;t die at 50C. Updated kernel! No more random System UI crashes. Network indicatior fixed  Very Important Notice:-  From now on Hentai and PE will have completely different trees, feature and changelog, please don&amp;rsquo;t compare them!!!!  You don&amp;rsquo;t need to , but if you want donate:-  PayPal:- https://www.paypal.me/rohanhasabe8 UPI-ID:- hasaberohan@icici  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Violet PE June Changelog!</title>
      <link>https://hasaber.me/posts/pe-violet-june-changelog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 19:51:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hasaber.me/posts/pe-violet-june-changelog/</guid>
      <description>Source Side changes:-  June security patch Fixed recorder crashes Improved network traffic indicator Improved volume panel on left side (for supported devices) Updated translations Fix vibration enabled when battery saver is enabled Implement quick QS brightness slider Updated some prebuilt system apps Other minor changes  Device Side changes:-  QC3 is fixed now! OTA will only work if you are using AOSP recovery! If you are using TWRP please download the full build!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Basics</title>
      <link>https://hasaber.me/posts/git-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 21:24:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hasaber.me/posts/git-basics/</guid>
      <description>Git is a free and open source distributed version control system designed to handle everything from small to very large projects with speed and efficiency. Which can be installed on your Windows/MacOS X/Linux computer!  Installation  For Windows Computers go ahead and download the Git client from https://git-scm.com/download/win , just accept all the permissions basically keep clicking ok until the installation is done, don’t change anything you don’t know. For Linux Computers just open terminal and type  “sudo apt-get install git” click enter, git will be installed in 1-2 minutes according to you internet connection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opensource and Monetization</title>
      <link>https://hasaber.me/posts/opensource-and-monetisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 03:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hasaber.me/posts/opensource-and-monetisation/</guid>
      <description>Seems like these don’t go hand in hand, does it?
Lemme view it from my perspective.
Recently there was an android kernel developer who tried to monetize his kernel in the most inappropriate way possible. It became disastrous and he became a meme in that process. He was forced to leave development, forever.
So, is monetizing opensource software cancerous?
Red Hat is the global leader in open source software solutions — and has a clear strategy in how to generate revenue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$whoami</title>
      <link>https://hasaber.me/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hasaber.me/about/</guid>
      <description>I am Rohan Hasabe, a 18 year old, Engineering 2nd Year student!, popularly known around the internet world as Hasaber8 .
If you ﬁnd some­one with the user­name Hasaber8 on any platform, you can be mostly sure its me</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Me</title>
      <link>https://hasaber.me/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hasaber.me/contact/</guid>
      <description>I would be available on Telegram almost all time except my sleep xD. Best would be ping me there for relevant things, please don&amp;rsquo;t spam me. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have Telegram, sorry! For any formal correspondence, Email which has become too formal: [rohanhasabe8@gmail.com](mailto: rohanhasabe8@gmail.com)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>